omg.org 2001-11-07

# Privacy Statement

Protecting the security and privacy of your Personal Information is important to Object Management Group and to the way we conduct our business in compliance with laws on privacy, data protection and data security in the countries in which we maintain Web sites. We hope the policy outlined below will help you understand what information Object Management Group may collect, how Object Management Group uses and safeguards that information and with whom we may share it.  
  
* * *

## Personal Information  
  
Through our Web sites, Object Management Group will not collect any personally-identifiable information about you (e.g., your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address ("Personal Information")), unless you voluntarily choose to provide it to us (e.g., by registration, survey). If you do not want your Personal Information collected, please do not submit it to us.

When you do provide us with Personal Information, we usually use it to respond to your inquiry, process your order or provide you access to specific account information. Also, to support our customer relationship with you: 

  * we may store and process Personal Information and share it with our worldwide affiliates to better understand your business needs and how we can improve our products and services; or 
  * we (or a third party on our behalf) may use Personal Information to contact you about the Object Management Group's offer in support of your business needs or to conduct online surveys to understand better our customers' needs and profiles.

If you choose not to have your Personal Information used to support our customer relationship (especially direct-marketing or market-research), we will respect your choice. We do not now (and do not intend to) sell, rent or otherwise market your Personal Information to third parties.  
  
* * *

## Non-Personal Information Collected Automatically  
  
When you access our Web sites, we may automatically (i.e., not by registration) collect information that is not personally-identifiable (e.g., type of Internet browser and computer operating system used; domain name of the Web site from which you came; number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed). We may use this information and share it with our worldwide affiliates to measure the use of our Web sites and improve their content.  
  
* * *

## "Cookies" -- Information Placed Automatically on Your  
 Computer  
  
When you view one of our Web sites, we may store some information on your computer in the form of a "Cookie" to automatically recognize you the next time you visit. Cookies can help us in many ways, for example, by allowing us to tailor a Web site to better match your interests or to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it each time. If you choose not to be recognized, please refer to your Internet browser to erase Cookies from your computer hard drive, block all Cookies or receive a warning before a Cookie is stored.  
  
* * *

## Children  
  
No Personal Information should be submitted to the Object Management Group Web sites by children without the consent of their parent or guardian. Object Management Group encourages all parents or guardians to instruct their children in the safe and responsible use of their Personal Information while using the Internet. Object Management Group will not knowingly collect or use any Personal Information collected from children for any purpose whatsoever, including disclosure to third parties.  
  
* * *

## Security  
  
Object Management Group takes precautions to ensure the security of your Personal Information and strives to keep it accurate. We carefully protect your Personal Information from loss, destruction, falsification, manipulation, and unauthorized access or unauthorized disclosure.  
  
* * *

## Links to Other Web Sites  
  
The Object Management Group Web sites contain links to other Web sites. Object Management Group is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web sites.  

## Questions and Comments  
  
If you have any questions or comments about the Object Management Group Privacy Policy (e.g., to review and update your Personal Information), please "contact" us at "[webmaster@omg.org](mailto:webmaster@omg.org)" by inserting the words "Privacy Policy" in the "Subject" line. As the Internet matures, so will our Privacy Policy. We will post changes to our Privacy Policy on this page as soon as the commitment has been made to alter any existing policy.
